Guide to the Samuel F. Pryor Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Samuel F. Pryor papers
1927-1984
1950-1984
MS 1481
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(3 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, newspaper clippings, and photographs documenting the life and career of Samuel F. Pryor and his friendship with Charles and Anne Morrow Lindbergh.
Pryor, Samuel F., Jr. (Samuel Frazier), 1898-1985
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lawrence Pryor, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Samuel F. Pryor Papers, which date from 1927-1984, consist of personal papers including correspondence, writings, photographs, and printed material, which document Pryor's friendship with Anne and Charles Lindbergh as well as his collecting interests. The papers contain virtually no records relating to Pryor's work with Pan American Airways, the Republican Party, or the Bureau of Narcotics, though these aspects of his career are reflected in printed material about Pryor and in scattered congratulatory letters from prominent individuals in government. Lawrence A. Pryor donated his father's papers to the Yale University Library in 1988.
The bulk of the papers date after 1950 and concern the Lindberghs. The papers include letters from friends and members of the general public, who either knew Lindbergh, admired him, or had visited his burial site on Maui. In addition the papers contain Pryor's collection of photographs, clippings, and other printed material relating to the Lindberghs.
Biographical / Historical
SAMUEL FRAZIER PRYOR, JR., 1898-1985
Samuel Frazier Pryor, Jr., was born on March 1, 1898, in Ferguson, Missouri. He attended the Taft School in Connecticut and received a Ph.B. from Yale University in 1921. After graduation, Pryor worked for the Remington Cash Register Company and from 1925-1941 was associated with the American Brake Shoe & Foundry Company and its subsidiary, the Southern Wheel Company. Pryor served as eastern treasurer of the Republican National Committee and in the 1940 presidential campaign was vice-chairman of the Republican National Committee and was in charge of Wendell Willkie's eastern headquarters.
In July, 1941, he became vice-president, director, and assistant to the president of Pan American World Airways, a position he held until his retirement in 1965. During World War II he headed Pan American's airport development program and directed the construction of fifty strategic air bases in South America and Africa. For this work President Truman awarded him the Medal of Merit in 1946.
Pryor graduated from the U.S. Treasury Narcotic Agent's School in Washington and served as an agent and advisor for the Bureau of Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs in the Justice Department. He represented the government at meetings of Interpol, the International Criminal Police Organization.
In 1926 Pryor married Mary Taylor Allerdice. They had five children: Mary Taylor (Mrs. Lowell Thomas, Jr.), Samuel Frazier, Taylor Allerdice, Frances Bailey (Mrs. Robert Hawes), and Lawrence Allerdice. The Pryor household also included many animals, among them a gibbon ape named Kippy. They Pryors lived in Greenwich, Connecticut, but also maintained a ranch on the island of Maui in Hawaii. The Pryors were close friends of Anne and Charles Lindbergh and sold the Lindberghs a portion of their Maui property. Pryor's personal interests included a large collection of dolls and mechanical banks. Pryor published an informal autobiography, All God's Creatures, with John Burnett, in 1982. Samuel Pryor died on September 18, 1985.
Maui (Hawaii); Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1906-2001; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974; Pryor, Samuel F., Jr. (Samuel Frazier), 1898-1985
- Additional Material, Accession 1988-M-093
  - A -C (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bruce Museum, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh Fund, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Tom C., Circa 1950-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D -J (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gurney, Harlan A., 1977-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Halleck, Charles A., 1941-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 1965, 1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - K -M (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lindbergh
    - Letters written by Anne Morrow Lindbergh to Samuel and Mary Tay Pryor, 1968-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Photocopies of Anne Morrow Lindbergh correspondence with others, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Anne Morrow Lindbergh's notes on the Lindbergh material in the possession of Samuel Pryor, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Typescripts of speeches and addresses given by Anne Morrow Lindbergh, 1968, 1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letters written by Charles A. Lindbergh to Samuel and Mary Tay Pryor, 1953-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Photocopies and originals of Charles A. Lindbergh's correspondence with others, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Lindbergh photographs, 1925-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Typescripts and originals of speeches and writings of Charles A. Lindbergh, 1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lindbergh property on Maui, 1969-1975, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1927, 1939-1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1977 April-May (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1977 June-August (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lindberghs: printed material concerning, 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - N -Z (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - National Aeronautic Association: Lindbergh bust dedication, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Pryor, Samuel
    - Booklists, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Photographs, 1959, 1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Printed material about or relating to Pryor, Circa 1930-1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Writings, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Unidentified, 1952-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)